

Shivam Mishra Full-Stack Web Developer

ABOUT ME

An inspired MERN stack developer, always curious about new problems and learning new things in order to deliver out of the box solutions with complete ownership. Hands on experience in solving close to 500 DSA problems and developing five MERN based projects

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTION

TensorFlow

• TensorFlow is an end-to-end open source platform for machine learning. It has a comprehensive, flexible ecosystem of tools, libraries, and community resources that lets researchers push the state-ofthe-art in ML and developers easily build and deploy ML-powered applications.

<u>Layer5io</u>

· Layer5's cloud native application and infrastructure management software enables organizations to expect more from their infrastructure. We embrace developer-defined infrastructure.

PROJECTS

Shopping Ganga

Source Code

- This MERN stack e-commerce site is a powerful Backend Heavy and comprehensive online store, designed and built individually, with intuitive design and user-friendly interface. Webapp provides admin panel with administration privileges like product listing, user profile management, delivery data.
- Features -export Data in PDF, sending mails, PayPal, cart management, order summary, filter, search.
- Tech Stack ReactJs, NodeJS, Mongo Atlas ,PayPal API, Material UI.

Practo.com Clone

Source Code

Practo is the world's leading healthcare platform that connects millions of patients with hundreds of thousands of healthcare providers around the world and helps people make better healthcare decisions.

- Developed along with a team of 4 members in one week.
- Created a dynamic profile page for doctors using redux and appointment list for users.
- Tech Stack React, Node, MongoAtlas, Chakra-UI, Redux, ExpressJS, BootStrap, Cyclic, Middleware.

<u>RavenEye</u>

Source Code

This is a video calling application where users can call other user and will also have the capability to mute their mic and audio.

- Features -real time chat functionality. It's also a modern PWA so users can install it on their devices like other native apps.Unlimited duration calls, Chat Notifications, Chat in real-time.
 - Tech Stack PWA, ReactJS, JavaScript, SocketIO, WebRTC, Realtime.

MY CONTACT

shivammmishra7@gmail.com

+91 9870031209

Shivam Mishra

https://shivam-m-7.vercel.app/

https://github.com/shivam-m-7

Surat, Gujarat

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engross Infotech

Full Stack Developer

· Serving on an International E-Commerce Project Lakeshore using technology like KnockoutJS, Jaya, Endeca, Bootstrap, Jquery, XM, and SQL. 06/2023-current Surat, Gujarat

<u>Om System Design</u>

Full Stack Developer

- In addition to contributing to a number of projects implementing ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, SQL, C#, SQL, Javascript, Bootstrap, and Git technologies, I was in the role of designing, building, and maintaining a web application.
- projects on AWS and Azure cloud platforms and hosted

05/2021-06/20223 Surat, Gujarat

<u>Om System Design</u>

Asp.Net Intern

Contributed in a product, school management system using TechStack C#, javascript, SQL, AJAX. 06/2018-01/2019 Surat, Gujarat

Tech Skill

- React
- Java OOps
- C# Flask
- Node JS Mongo DB
- Mysql Git
- Heroku AWS
- Express JavaScript
- DSA
- Python

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Masai School

Full-stack Web Development course May-2022 to March-2023

- **Gujarat Technological University** Bachelor's in I.T Engineering June-2018 to May-2021
- **Gujarat Technological University** Diploma in I.T Engineering

June-2015 to May-2018